VAIBHAV MAHNA

1203-37 Vanier Drive Kitchener, ON N2C 2P6 Vaibhavmahna56@gmail.com Vaibhavmahna@github.io 226-600-7108

OBJECTIVES:

To work in the Networking field using knowledge and expertise gained from my education.

SUMMARY OF SKILLS:

ITIL Foundations – Support Agreements
Working with SQL server database administration
Worked on Microsoft Exchange 2016
Practical work on Hyper V and Window Server 2012 r2 standard
Familiar with packet tracer for Cisco hardware.
Worked on storage area network and network area storage
Worked on Linux Centos (Fedora) Ubuntu 16.4 (Debian)
Working with Esxi 6.0

Window Server 2012 R2: Installed domain controller, Additional Domain Controller, WDS, Active Directory, DHCP, DNS, MDM and Data-sharing, WSUS, Remote access, VPN and Group Policy Object

Installed and Configured Hyper-V and VMware machines and switches for connectivity

EDUCATION:

Applied Network Infrastructure and System Administration Post Grad Certificate

Conestoga College, Kitchener, Ontario

Sep2017-Dec2018

Program GPA – 3.92

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Northern India Engineering College, IP University, Delhi, India Percentage – 83.02% June2012-May2016

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE:

Maintenance Technician at NCR

Feb2019-Present

Presently working on a project in Blackberry HQ, Waterloo

WORK EXPERIENCE:

 Food Bank, Conestoga College, Kitchener, Ontario
 Food Bank Leader
 Managing the inventory and visit record in the Food Bank Sept2018-Dec2018

2. Tim Hortons, Conestoga College, Kitchener, Ontario

Oct2017-Feb2019

Team Member

Greet the customers and guide them regarding products available on the menu Familiar with payment systems

PROJECTS:

1. Messaging Application

Installed and configured the Kerio Connect application on Linux with features of email, messaging and calendaring. Also, connected the Linux machine with the Active Directory to manage the users. Setup the security policies for the users.

2. Managing the Infrastructure of three companies after merger

Followed ITIL and configured the Active Directory for all the three companies. Pushed the group policies of the larger company to the other two companies. Created a Network Layout for the new environment on the packet tracer.

3. ITIL Implementation

Listed the ITIL steps to be followed for the scenario where my team represented an ISP. We had to upgrade the ISP bandwidth from 1Gbps to 10Gbps.

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE:

Microsoft Window Server 2012 Microsoft SQL Server 2014 Red Hat Linux 6 Windows PowerShell 4.0 Cisco Packet tracer 7.1.1 ESXI 6.0 Hyper V Microsoft Window Server 2016 Microsoft Exchange Server 2016 ITIL foundation Microsoft Office products Windows 10; 7 Linux Centos 7.0

AWARDS AND RECOGNITION:

Listed in the Deans Honor List for excellent academic performance for 4 Semesters Graduation with Distinction for securing 90% and above in the course

VOLUNTEERING:

Provide guidance information to new students to Canada